

JAMES GIFFORD

WEB DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

I am a professional, self-motivated web developer with over 10 years of experience using open-source technologies to create websites, applications, and services both collaboratively and independently while following the latest coding standards and organizational styles.

FOLLOW ME

Website jamesgifford.com

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/jamesgifford

Facebook facebook.com/jameswgifford

GitHub github.com/jamesgifford

CONTACT MF



503 - 9<u>75</u> - 54<u>75</u>



jameswgifford@gmail.com



2586 NW 3rd Terrace Gresham, OR 97030

EXPERIENCE

Software Programmer at STAFFING ROBOT

Dec 2015 - Present

When my contract was finished I was hired on to continue working on the company's client projects. These involved websites created with WordPress using custom plugins and various external APIs.

PHP WordPress JavaScript jQuery MySQL CSS Sass HTML

Freelance Software Programmer at STAFFING ROBOT

Mar 2015 - Dec 2015

I was hired as a contractor to work on a specific project involving rewriting a homegrown inventory management and ordering system from the ground up using the Codelgniter PHP framework.

HP Codelgniter JavaScript jQuery MySQL CSS HTML

Freelance Web Developer at SHIFTWISE

Jun 2013 - Dec 2015

My primary focus was maintaining the Mighty Nurse website which is one of the largest nursing training and staffing communities. Duties included adding features, fixing bugs, and server upkeep.

PHP WordPress JavaScript jQuery MySQL CSS HTML

Web Application Engineer at SUBSTANCE

Aug 2012 - Jun 2013

I worked on many of our client websites which were heavily customized WordPress applications. My roles included backend programmer, frontend developer, quality assurance, and consultant.

PHP WordPress JavaScript jQuery MySQL CSS Sass HTML

Lead Web Developer at CD BABY

May 2008 - Aug 2012

As Lead Developer, my duties included coordinating with front-end and back-end developers as well as management in the architecting and support of our site building web application built with PHP.

PHP Codelgniter JavaScript jQuery MySQL PostgreSQL CSS HTML

Programmer at HOT OFF THE PRESS

May 2005 - May 2008

My primary responsibilities included developing tools and reports in order to provide data for the different departments within the company.

PHP Codelgniter JavaScript jQuery MySQL CSS HTML

SKILLS

LANGUAGES	FRAMEWORKS	CMS	DATABASES
PHP	Laravel	WordPress	MySQL
JavaScript	Codelgniter	Drupal	PostgreSQL
HTML	CakePHP	Joomla	SQL Server
CSS	jQuery	Concrete5	SQLite
Swift	Angular.js	Magento	MongoDB
Python	Bootstrap	MODX	Redis

EDUCATION

WESTERN OREGON UNIVERSITY

2001 - 2003

I earned my Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (cum laude) here with a minor in Mathematics.

PORTLAND STATE UNIVERSITY

1999 - 2001

Here I continued my studies of Computer Science and Mathematics plus some Business studies. \\

PACIFIC UNIVERSITY 1998 - 1999

As a freshman I started majoring in Computer Science with some Japanese and Mathematics.